我们的故事开始于
Our story begins high over New York City...
一间纽约市的属于也许是这个世界上最不像天才的…
in the luxurious penthouse apartment...
楼顶豪华别墅里。
of perhaps the most unlikely genius the world has ever known.
对不起，被你撞见我在做瑜伽了。
Sorry. You caught me doing my yoga.
你以为我是一只倒过来的狗？
You were expecting downward dog, perhaps?
我的名字是皮博迪。
My name is Mr. Peabody.
因为我们将会相处一段时间…
And since we're going to be spending some time together...
所以我愿意先和你介绍一下我自己。
I'd like to tell you a little bit about myself.
当我还是一只小狗的时候…
You see, ever since I was a pup...
很显然我与众不同。
it was clear that I was different.
我曾试着融进狗群…
I tried to fit in...
不，谢了。
No, thank you.
但总是做不到。
But never could.
随着我逐渐长大，我见到越来越多的“狗友”……
As I grew, I saw more and more of my littermates...
被新家庭领养了。
being chosen by their new families.
但出于某些原因，我从来没被认领过。
But for some reason, I never was.
来吧小狗狗，去捡回来！
Come on, boy! Fetch the stick!
为什么？你想要我捡回来让你再扔一次么？
But why? Won't you just throw it again?
这只是一项毫无意义的运动。
It's an exercise in futility.
妈，我不喜欢这只狗。他太冷嘲热讽了。
I don't want this one, Mommy. He's sarcastic.
等等！回来！回来扔树枝啊！
Wait, wait! Come back! Throw the stick.
我会坐着不动，我会后脚站立，我甚至会和你握手！
I'll stay, I'll heel, I'll even shake hands.
汪，汪？
Bark, bark?
所以，没有我自己的家庭…
So, without a family of my own...
我投身于知识…
I dedicated myself to the pursuit of knowledge...
文化，还有体育的追求。
culture, and athletics.
我在哈佛获得了学位。
I received my degree at Harvard.
史上第一只狗狗，是的。
Vale-dog-torian, of course.
接着，我又投身于造福人类。
And then, I devoted myself to helping mankind.
我开阔了可再生能源新技术。
I pioneered new techniques in alternative energy.
解决了国际争端。
Resolved geopolitical conflicts around the globe.
而且在我的空闲时间…
And in my spare time...
我发明了打拳头式招呼，下卧式撒尿，可撕扯裤子…
I invented the fist bump, planking, tearaway pants...
自动调音…
Auto-Tune...
背部翱骊（一种滑板动作）…
the backside ollie...
还有准巴舞。
and Zumba.
但最令我自豪的是我的儿子，谢尔曼。
But what I'm most proud of is my son, Sherman.
嗨，皮博迪先生。
Hi, Mr. Peabody.
你告诉他们WABAC了吗？
Have you told them about the WABAC?
我刚好要说。
I was just getting to that.
当我收养谢尔曼的时候，我发誓要成为最好的父亲。
When I adopted Sherman, I vowed to be the best father I could be.
为了让他对这个世界的神奇做好准备，无论是过去或者现在。
To prepare him for all the wonders of the world, present and past.
谢尔曼给了我灵感让我发明我一生中最棒的东西…
And so, Sherman inspired the greatest invention of my life...
时光机器。
a time machine.
当然了，时间旅行是有点难以预料的。
Of course, time travel can be a bit unpredictable.
在时空穿梭的路上一定会有一点磕碰。
There are bound to be a few mishaps along the way.
打个比方，倾斜的比萨斜塔一开始并不是倾斜的。
Let's just say, the Leaning Tower of Pisa wasn't always leaning.
但是没有别的事情比亲身经历历史事件更赞的了。
But there's nothing like learning the lessons of history firsthand.
对不，谢尔曼？
Right, Sherman?
我们今天要去哪里呢，皮博迪先生？
Where are we going today, Mr. Peabody?
不是“哪里”，谢尔曼。
Not "where," Sherman.
应该是“什么时候”。
"When."
法国大革命——1789
这是我见过的最大的房子了！
This is the biggest house I've ever seen!
这是凡尔赛宫，玛丽·安托瓦内特的家。
It's the Palace of Versailles, home of Marie Antoinette.
你知道的，她有一件事最出名。
You know, she was mostly famous for one thing.
蛋糕！
Cake!
我爱死蛋糕了！
I love cake so much.
看来玛丽·安托瓦内特真的超喜欢蛋糕，皮博迪先生。
Marie Antoinette sure likes cake, Mr. Peabody.
确实。
Indeed, she does.
玛丽·安托瓦内特对一切涂有糖霜的东西…
Marie was a womanwith a prodigious appetite...
都有特别惊人的胃口。
for all things covered with frosting.
但她在吃的方面花的那么多钱使她成了社会批判的众矢之的。
But her expensive tastes made her the target of much criticism.
- Why?       - Because, Sherman...
-为什么？    - 因为，谢尔曼…
在玛丽的统治下，法国的老百姓都极度贫穷。
during Marie's reign, the common people of France were exceedingly poor.
你有面包么？
You've got any bread?
没有！我极度贫穷！
No! I'm exceedingly poor.
现在我们可以吃些蛋糕了吗？
Now, can we have some cake?
好的。（法语）
Mais, oui.
哦，对了，对不起。
Oh, yeah, sorry.
“请问”我们可不可以吃些蛋糕？
"May we" have some cake?
是的是的！
Mais, oui!
也许她的头发盖住了耳朵让她听不到我说话。
Maybe she can't hear me through the hair.
谢尔曼，女王的意思是…
Sherman, what the queen means is...
让他们吃蛋糕吧！
Let them eat cake!
当女王听到巴黎的贫穷人民甚至没钱卖面包时…
When the queen heard the poor of Paris could not even buy bread...
她只是说，“给他们吃点蛋糕吧！”
she said, "Let them eat cake."
不！
No!
我亲耳听到的！
I heard it myself.
-这是丑闻！              -这是暴行！
- It's a scandal!     - It's an outrage!
把女王赶下台！
Down with the queen!
废掉君主制！
Down with the monarchy!
等等！
Wait!
是什么蛋糕？
What kind of cake?
真是个美妙的派对，亲爱的女王。
Smashing party, Your Majesty.
但现在，我担心谢尔曼和我应该…
But now, I'm afraid Sherman and I must be...
谢尔曼？谢尔曼？
Sherman? Sherman?
谢尔曼！
Sherman!
谢尔曼？
Sherman?
谢尔曼！这里，谢尔曼。
Sherman! Here, Sherman.
嗨，皮博迪先生。
Hey, Mr. Peabody.
你在这干嘛？
What are you doing in here?
试试这些蛋糕。
Trying these other cakes.
这个大的蛋糕涂满了奶油和草莓…
There's one in here with whipped cream and strawberries that's...
-太棒了！                 -谢尔曼…
- pretty fantastic!      - Sherman...
你忘了我告诉过你为什么在这期间要跟紧我？
don't you remember why I told you to stay close to me during the French Revolution?
因为在法国大革命之后…
Because after the French Revolution...
-一切都会被毁掉？      -差不多。
- it was gonna rain?   - Close.
我说过，“在法国大革命到来时…
I said, "After the French Revolution comes...
会是一场腥风血雨！”
the Reign of Terror!"
把贵族都给抓起来！
Round up the aristocrats.
女王和她的贵族狗友…
The queen and her aristocratic cronies...
要为他们的暴政付出代价！
must pay the price for their gluttony.
我们要把他们像狗一样都杀光！
We will slaughter them like the dogs they are.
先从这只开始！
Starting with this one!
皮博迪先生！
Mr. Peabody!
我应该做什么？
What should I do?
什么都不用做，谢尔曼。站在那儿别动。
Nothing, Sherman. Just stay right there.
但是，皮博迪先生！
But, Mr. Peabody!
一切都会没事的，谢尔曼。
Everything is going to be fine, Sherman.
站在那儿就好。
Just stay right there.
砍了他的头！
Off with his head!
皮博迪先生
Mr. Peabody!
一个哈密瓜？
A cantaloupe?
最低等的水果。
The lowest of the fruits.
竟然有人敢用这个瓜来耍我？
Who dares to insult me with this melon?
抓住那只狗！
Get that dog!
皮博迪先生，你是怎么逃出来的？
Mr. Peabody, how did you escape?
那很简单，谢尔曼。
It's simple, Sherman.
我注意到了沟井盖间的距离…
I noticed the distance between the sewer lids...
算出了一定有一个沟井盖正对着断头台下方…
reasoned that there must be one directly under the guillotine platform...
记住了篮子下面松动的木板…
noted the loose board under the basket...
计算出太阳光在你的眼镜上反射的角度…
computed the angle at which the setting sun
would bounce off your glasses...
暂时照瞎刽子手的眼睛时…
momentarily blinding the executioner...
我看准了这个时机偷来刽子手的哈密瓜…
and chose that moment to swipe the executioner's melon...
哈密瓜的重量让那块松动的木板翻转过来，促成了我的逃脱。
giving me the added weight to tip the boards, facilitating my exit.
那太不可思议了！
That's amazing!
没有这么夸张。
It's not amazing.
我只不过是保住了我的头罢了。
It was just a matter of keeping my head.
哈哈太搞笑了，“保住了你的头。”
"Keeping your head."
笑点在哪？
I don't get it.
他在这里，追上去！
There he is! After them!
这边，谢尔曼，快点！
Come, Sherman, quick!
这水的味道真糟糕！
This water tastes terrible.
有意思的是，这些不是水。
Interestingly, that's not water.
抓住你了！
I've got you now.
你确实抓住我了。罗伯斯庇尔先生（法国大革命时期政治家）。
Indeed you have, Monsieur Robespierre.
你抓人太厉害了。
And what a master of the chase you are.
你注意到了？
You noticed?
当然。
Of course.
像这样让我腹背受敌。
Doubling back on me like that.
真是天才。
That was genius.
谢谢。
Thank you.
我只是希望你不要抓走我的小伙伴。
I just hope you don't take my little confederate, here.
我完全靠他了。
I depend on him so completely.
过来这里！
Get over here, you.
糟糕！你太聪明了！
Drats! You're devilishly clever.
我知道。而且我还比你快。
I know. And much quicker than you as well.
但你有比这快吗？
But are you quick enough for this?
看见了吗？多快啊！
See? Quick!
是很快，不过就是不太聪明。
Quick, yes, but not too smart.
另一个哈密瓜！
Another cantaloupe!
你的剑！
Your sword!
好了，谢尔曼，看来考验一只狗的剑术的时候到了。
All right, Sherman, looks like it's time for a little pop quiz in the art of fencing.
开始！
Go!
进攻！回避！猛刺！再来一次！
Attack! Parry! Thrust! Repeat!
-不要。  -再刺！
- No.    - Remise!
好小子！
Good boy!
打不中了！
You missed!
我从来不会打不中。
I never miss.
快上来！
Hop on!
耶！
Yeah!
-你闻到了吗，谢尔曼？           -不是我放的屁，皮博迪先生。
- Do you smell that, Sherman?   - It wasn't me, Mr. Peabody.
我知道那不是你。
I know it wasn't you.
那是地下供气系统里的沼气。
It's the methane gas in the sewer system.
沼气会在306华氏度爆炸…
And given the fact that it ignites at 306 degrees Fahrenheit...
我们要利用它…
we're about to use it...
炸掉这里！
to blast out of here!
抓紧！
Hang on!
哇哦！
Wow!
降落得挺不错的，对不谢尔曼？
Nice landing, eh, Sherman?
那么，你今天学到了什么，谢尔曼？
So, what did you learn today, Sherman?
法国大革命真是疯了!
That French Revolution was crazy.
何以见得？
How so?
那些伙计把别人的头给砍下来…
All those guys getting their heads chopped off...
却没有人站出来说这是不对的。
and nobody standing up and saying it wasn't right.
而且，玛丽·安托瓦内特明明就可以避免这场革命…
And think, Marie Antoinette could have avoided the whole revolution...
只需要她发布一项法令把面包分发到穷人中去。
if she'd simply issued an edict to distribute bread amongst the poor.
但是那样做的话，她就没法吃她的点心了。
But then, she couldn't have had her dessert.
为什么不可以，皮博迪先生？
Why not, Mr. Peabody?
因为，谢尔曼，鱼和熊掌不可兼得。
Because, Sherman, you can't have your cake and edict, too.
笑点在哪？
I don't get it.
我们明天去哪里，皮博迪先生？
Where are we gonna go tomorrow, Mr. Peabody?
古罗马？狂野西部？1492年？
Ancient Rome? The Wild West? 1492?
不，谢尔曼，这些地方我们一个都不会去。
No, Sherman, tomorrow we won't be going to any of those places.
为什么不？
Why not?
因为明天的冒险…
Because tomorrow's adventure...
需要你自己去搞定。
is one that you're going to be taking all on your own.
什么意思，皮博迪先生？
What do you mean, Mr. Peabody?
你忘了吗？
Don't you remember?
明天你第一天上学。
It's your first day of school.
-我可以开吗？     -当然不行。
- Can I drive?    - Of course not.
要记住，谢尔曼，记住拼写规则。
Remember, Sherman, "i" before "e," except after "c."
我知道了，皮博迪先生。
I know, Mr. Peabody!
还有别忘了加法交换律。
And don't forget about the commutative principle.
2加3等于3加2.
Two plus three equals three plus two.
我知道了，皮博迪先生！
I know, Mr. Peabody!
如果你不得不去厕所的话…
And if you have to go to the bathroom...
只要勇敢举起你的手然后说，“老师我要去厕所。”就好了。
just raise your hand proudly and say, "I have to go."
我会的，皮博迪先生。
I will, Mr. Peabody.
还有要记住，2号铅笔在大多数时候是最标准的…
And remember, the No. 2 pencil is standard for most uses...
但有时候1号铅笔也很好用。
but there are times when a No. 1 comes in handy.
我在你书包里放了一张表格…
I left a little pencil chart in your backpack...
当你不知道要用哪一种的时候就去查它。
which you can consult if it ever becomes a judgment call.
我认为我应付得来！
I think I'll be okay!
-好了，再见了，皮博迪先生。      -等等。
- Okay, bye, Mr. Peabody.       - Wait.
-放学后见。                  -谢尔曼！
- See you after school.      - Sherman!
我得走了。我还要去社团签到。
I gotta go. I gotta sign up for the clubs.
没有人比我更支持去参加这类增进兄弟情义的组织。
No one is more in favor of participation in fraternal organizations than I.
但在你走之前，我想要你拿着这个。
But before you go, I want you to have this.
谢谢。这是什么？
Thanks. What is it?
一个狗哨子。
A dog whistle.
它坏了，皮博迪先生。
It doesn't work, Mr. Peabody.
它好好的，谢尔曼。
It works fine, Sherman.
它发出的频率只有狗才可以听到。
It's just a frequency only dogs can hear.
太酷了。
Cool.
让这个小纪念品时时刻刻提醒你…
Let that little keepsake be a reminder to you...
无论你面临着什么挑战，无论看起来我距离你多远…
that no matter what challenges you face, no matter how far away I might seem...
再见，皮博迪先生！
Bye, Mr. Peabody!
我都会和你在一起。
I'm with you.
乔治·华盛顿。
George Washington.
谁可以告诉我他是谁？
Who can tell me who he is?
我！我可以！我可以！
Me! I can! I can!
谢尔曼。
Sherman.
美国的第一位总统。
The first president of the United States of America.
真棒。
Good job.
当华盛顿总统还是一个小孩的时候…
And when President Washington was a little boy...
他砍掉了什么树？
what kind of tree did he cut down?
我！我！我！
Me! Me! Me!
-佩妮？         -一棵樱桃树。
- Penny?        - A cherry tree.
-那是瞎编的。       -“瞎编的”是什么树？
- Apocryphal.       - What kind of tree is that?
那不是树。那是一个词。“瞎编的”。
It's not a tree. It's a word. "Apocryphal."
我的意思是这个故事是瞎编的。
It means that story is not true.
-真的？         -是的。
- Really?       - Yeah.
乔治·华盛顿从来没有砍过一棵樱桃树…
George Washington never cut down a cherry tree...
而且他也没有说过“我不可以撒谎”。
and he never said he couldn't lie.
人们编造这些故事出来教小孩说撒谎是不好的…
People made those stories up to teach kids a lesson about lying...
但这些故事本来就不是真的。
but they're not true.
虽说他确实在1776年的圣诞节横渡德拉瓦河。
He did cross the Delaware River, Christmas night, 1776, though.
我爸在今年夏天带我去了那里。我们也渡过那条河。
My dad took me there this summer. We crossed it, too.
不过我摔进去了。
I fell in.
看起来有的人确实懂得历史，对不，佩妮？
Looks like someone really knows their history, huh, Penny?
真高兴认识你们。
It's really great meeting you guys.
也许有一天你们可以到我家来玩。
Maybe you can come over to my house sometime.
我可以给你看我的模型。那是个氢原子模型。
I could bring my new model. It's a hydrogen atom.
你只有一个？
You've only got one, huh?
看来我们得把它劈开才够我们分的了。
Guess we'll have to split it.
好笑话！
Good one!
看着，伙计们。
Check it, guys.
你在吃什么，谢尔曼？
What do you got there, Sherman?
嚼的还是咬的？
Kibbles or bits?
事实上，我在吃小萝卜，有机苹果汁，还有一个吞拿三明治。
Actually, I've got baby carrots, organic apple juice, and a tuna sandwich.
它富含超多的omega-3。
It's super-high in omega-3s.
所以，你吃人吃的东西对不。
So, you eat human food, huh?
当然，为什么不？
Yeah. Why wouldn't I?
因为你是条狗。
Because you're a dog.
我才不是。
No, I'm not.
你当然是。你爸是条狗，所以你也是。
Sure you are. Your dad is a dog, so you're a dog, too.
我想你搞混了。他们父子是收养关系。
I think you're confused. It's an adoptive relationship.
-闭嘴，卡尔。         -好吧。
- Zip it, Carl.       - Okay.
看看。捡回来！
Here, I'll show you. Fetch!
去啊，小狗狗。去吃你的午餐。
Go on, doggy. Go get your lunch.
去啊。
Go on.
去捡啊。
Go get it.
真丢脸。
The humiliation.
谢尔曼，去捡你的东西吃啊。
Sherman, go get your food.
就像一只乖小狗一样。
Make like a good little doggy.
-这是什么？         -这是我的！
- What's this?      - It's mine!
-还给我！            -这是什么？一个哨子？
- Give it back!      - What is it? A whistle?
这破烂东西居然坏了。
Stupid thing doesn't even work.
这是个狗哨子，佩妮。
It's a dog whistle, Penny.
它发出的频率只有狗才听得到。
It operates at a frequency that only dogs can hear.
-回去，卡尔。         -好吧。
- Back up, Carl.      - Okay.
佩妮，那哨子是我的私人财产。
Penny, that whistle is my private property.
-还给我！            -跳啊，狗狗，跳啊。
- Give it back!      - Jump, doggy, jump.
我不是一只狗。
I am not a dog.
来啊，谢尔曼。
Come on, Sherman!
承认吧。你就是一只狗。说啊。
Just admit it. You're a dog. Say it.
让我走！
Let me go!
除非你像一只狗一样求我不然我是不会放手的。
Not until you beg like a dog.
快啊，谢尔曼，求我啊！
Come on, Sherman. Beg!
开打，开打，开打！
Fight, fight, fight!
谢尔曼先生，谢谢你收到临时通知后赶来…
Mr. Peabody, thank you for coming in on such short notice...
来讨论一下谢尔曼的问题。
to discuss the problem with Sherman.
没关系的，博迪校长。
It's not a problem at all, Principal Purdy.
我完全考虑过了。
I fully expected this.
-真的？        -是的。
- You did?     - Yes.
而且，和谢尔曼有关的资料，我都准备好了。
And, as with all things Sherman-related, I prepared for it.
这有一份课程表写清楚了谢尔曼通过的高等预科课程…
Here's a curriculum that takes Sherman's advanced preparation into account...
但绝对不会要求你安排谢尔曼在学校跳一级或更高。
but won't require you to have him skip one or more grades.
皮博迪先生…
Mr. Peabody...
这儿有一份预科代数工作表，一张高级阅读清单…
Here are some pre-algebra worksheets, an advanced reading list...
还有一个我创建的网站的链接所以他可以开始学中文了。
and a link to a website I created so he can start studying Mandarin Chinese.
是的中文，毕竟，中文是有前途的语言。
It is, after all, the language of the future.
皮博迪先生！
Mr. Peabody!
我也可没有说他不应该学法语，博迪校长。
I'm not saying he shouldn't study French, too, Principal Purdy.
我是说他两样都可以学。
I'm saying have him do both.
皮博迪先生！
Mr. Peabody!
什么？这样还不够？斯瓦希里语（坦桑尼亚的官方语言）？
What? Not enough? Swahili?
谢尔曼今天和人打架了。
Sherman got into a fight today.
哦，天哪。
Oh, dear.
保险起见…
Pictures were taken...
我给他们拍了照片。
for insurance purposes.
他咬了她。
He bit her.
我不得不说，这看起来对你很不利啊，皮博迪先生。
I must say, it doesn't look good for you, Mr. Peabody.
毕竟，你只是一条狗。
After all, you are a dog.
斗胆问一句，你说谁？
Who, may I ask, are you?
我是古宁恩夫人，来自儿童安全和保护局。
I am Ms. Grunion from the Bureau of Child Safety and Protection.
根据法律我们都会联系他们…在…
We're required by law to contact them whenever there's an...
有意外的时候。
incident.
谢尔曼从来就没有做过这样的事情。
Sherman has never done anything like this before.
我相信他一定有他的理由。
I'm sure he must have had a reason.
是的，那个女生确实有点霸道…
Well, the girl was being a bit of a bully...
安静，博迪！
Quiet, Purdy!
小孩子有点打闹是正常的。
It's normal for children to tease.
但不正常的是他们咬人。
It's not normal for them to bite.
显然，他咬人是因为被惹恼了。
Clearly, it's because of how he's being raised.
但在我看来，一只狗永远都不可能成为一个小男孩合适的父亲。
In my opinion, a dog can never be a suitable parent to a little boy.
我必须指出，古宁恩夫人…
I must point out, Ms. Grunion...
我是根据法律获得了谢尔曼的抚养权。
that I won the right to adopt Sherman in a court of law.
法律也可以撤销你的抚养权。
And the court can take it away from you.
明晚我会上你家去进行一项调查。
I'll be coming to your home tomorrow evening to conduct an investigation.
如果我发现，无论是在哪一方面，你不称职的话…
If I discover that you are, in any way, an unfit parent...
我可以预见你对谢尔曼的抚养权将会被撤销。
I will see to it Sherman is removed from your custody.
永远地。
Permanently.
我希望我已经说得够清楚了的。
I hope I've made myself clear.
够清楚的了。
Crystal.
很抱歉我咬了她，皮博迪先生。
I'm sorry I bit her, Mr. Peabody.
我再也不会那样做了。
I won't do it again.
你已经受罚了，当然不会再做了。
You're darn tooting you won't do it again.
这种随意暴力是完全不能被接受的。
This kind of wanton violence is totally unacceptable.
就算她再怎么坏，你也要以甘地为榜样。
And rather uncharacteristic, given how you feel about Mr. Gandhi.
究竟是什么激起了这场矛盾？
What on earth provoked it?
她叫我狗。
She called me a dog.
哦，好吧。
Well, all right then.
很感谢你告诉我。
Thank you for telling me.
睡吧。
Try and get some sleep.
我爱你，皮博迪先生。
I love you, Mr. Peabody.
我也很爱你，谢尔曼。
I have a deep regard for you as well, Sherman.
皮博迪先生…
Mr. Peabody...
你是个获得诺贝尔奖的科学家。
you are a Nobel Prize-winning scientist.
是全美国的领军顾问。
An advisor to heads of state.
是工业的领军人物。
A captain of industry.
为什么你想收养一个男孩？
Why would you want to adopt a boy?
因为，阁下…
Because, Your Honor...
当我第一次见到谢尔曼时，我想起了我是怎么开始我的生活的。
when I found Sherman, it reminded me of how I started out in life.
现在，我想给他那件我一直想拥有的东西。
And now, I want to give him the one thing I always wanted.
一个家。
A home.
你确定你有能力去面对那些抚养一个男孩所需要的…
And you're sure you're capable of meeting all the challenges...
挑战？
of raising a human boy?
所有应该预计的都预料到了，那会有多难？
With all due respect, how hard could it be?
那么非常好。
Very well, then.
如果一个男孩可以收养一只狗…
If a boy can adopt a dog...
为什么一只狗就不能收养一个男孩？
I see no reason why a dog cannot adopt a boy.
-爸爸！        -不，谢尔曼，不要“爸爸”。
- Da-da!       - No, Sherman, not "Da-da."
你要叫我“皮博迪先生。”
You shall call me "Mr. Peabody."
或者，更简洁一点，“皮博迪”就行了。
Or, in less formal moments, simply "Peabody."
对了。
That's right.
皮爸爸！
"Mr. Pea-baba."
-你在煮什么呢，皮博迪先生？          -没什么。
- What's cooking, Mr. Peabody?       - Nothing much.
只是几只太平洋大蟹加上一点百香果酱料。
Just a little Dungeness crab with a passion-fruit basil concassé.
一些杜松果大小的鹌鹑。
Some truffled quails in a juniper-berry reduction.
还有火焰冰激凌。
And Baked Alaska.
哇哦！今天是什么特别的日子么？
Wow! Is todaysome kind of special occasion?
猜猜看。
You could say.
-今天不是我的生日。            -没错，不是。
- It's not my birthday.        - No, it isn't.
-也不是你的生日。                -又对了。
- It's not your birthday.        - Right again.
今天是父亲节对不？
It's not Father's Day. Is it?
错了。今天不是父亲节。
Nope. It's not Father's Day.
是不是总统又要来和我们一起吃饭了？
Is the president coming to dinner again?
-不是。    -哦。
- No.      - Oh.
那么，谁要来和我们一起吃晚餐？
So, who's coming to dinner?
可以这么说，如果这场饭吃得顺利的话…
Let's just say, if the evening is a success...
我们就可以把“咬人”这件事抛到后脑勺去。
we can put this whole "biting" business behind us.
彼得逊一家！欢迎！
The Petersons! Welcome.
看吧，它只是条狗。              -保尔！
- So, he's literally a dog.     - Paul!
没事，没关系。
No, that's all right.
但是我更喜欢叫我，“受过教育的狗”。
Although, I prefer "literate dog."
真有趣！
That's funny.
这不有趣么，保尔？
Isn't that funny, Paul?
他平时不喜欢笑。
He's not a big laugher.
你们在收到通知后过来我们真的很荣幸。
We're so delighted you could make it on such short notice.
对不对啊，谢尔曼？
Aren't we, Sherman?
是啊，我们将会很享受今晚的晚餐，绝对地。
Yeah, we're interested in what's going on, that's for sure.
和佩妮打招呼，谢尔曼。
Say hello to Penny, Sherman.
你好，佩妮。
Hi, Penny.
你好，谢尔曼。
Hello, Sherman.
现在，为什么不带佩妮去看一下你的矿石藏品呢？
Now, why don't you go show Penny your mineral collection, Sherman?
她肯定会觉得你的那些晶体很神奇的。
I'm sure she'll find those new geodes of yours fascinating.
过来吧。
Come on.
我很高兴你接受了我的邀请。
I am so glad you accepted my invitation.
现在，孩子们可以在古宁恩夫人到来前解决他们的问题。
Now, the kids can resolve their differences before Ms. Grunion arrives.
你喊错对象了，狗先生。事实上…
You're barking up the wrong tree, mister. In fact...
要不是我的老婆佩蒂求情，我早就对你提出控告了。
if it weren't for Patty, I would have pressed charges already.
而且我还得告诉你，皮博迪先生。
And I have to tell you, Peabody...
就我的女儿而言，没有什么事比得上…
where my daughter is concerned, nothing is more important than...
你好。当然，我接受你的采访。
Hello. Sure, I'll take a survey.
一切还好吗？
Everything going swimmingly?
你干嘛不告诉我她要上这儿来？
Why didn't you tell me she was coming over here?
因为我不想让你担心。
Because I didn't want you to worry.
好吧，其实我是不想听你唠叨！
Okay, because I didn't want to listen to your bellyaching.
谢谢你很诚实。
Thank you for your honesty.
不用谢。
You're welcome.
我不知道你想要我们在这儿做什么。
I don't know what you think we're supposed to do in here anyway.
她恨我。
She hates me.
分享你的兴趣。讲个小笑话。
Share your interests. Tell a witty anecdote.
皮博迪先生…
Mr. Peabody...
我恨她。
I hate her.
谢尔曼，每一段友好的关系…
Sherman, every great relationship...
都是从一段矛盾开始的，而且随着时间的推移这种关系会更进一步发展。
starts from a place of conflict, and evolves into something richer.
祝你好运。
Bonne chance.
好好干。
Make it work.
别告诉她WABAC的事。
But don't tell her about the WABAC.
想都别想。
Don't even think about it.
皮博迪着太美妙了！
Peabody, that was amazing!
保尔，这不是很神奇吗？
Paul, wasn't that amazing?
我更喜欢摇滚乐。
I'm more into rock-'n'-roll.
我指的是弗拉门科民歌（一种西班牙民歌）。
I meant flamenco.
风笛？
Bagpipes?
迪吉里杜管（澳大利亚土著使用的一种乐器）。
Didgeridoo.
锡塔尔琴（印度的一种大弦弹拨乐器）。
Sitar.
钢鼓。
Steel drums.
长号。
Trombone.
木琴。
Xylophone.
非洲鼓？
Djembe?
气笛风琴。
Calliope.
双簧管。 短笛。
Oboe. Piccolo.
大号。冬不拉（乐器名）。
Tuba. Dobro.
滑动吹哨。约德尔唱法。
Slide whistle. Yodeling.
手摇风琴。卵形笛。
Hurdy-gurdy. Ocarina.
脚踏式风琴。钢锯。
Harmonium. Musical saw.
你知道不？这也许很赞…
You know what? This has been great...
但都是浪费时间。
but a complete waste of time.
现在咋门去找佩妮然后回家！
Now, let's get Penny and go home!
你还好吗，保尔？
Are you all right, Paul?
我…还行。
I'm... fine.
每当他紧张的时候他都会这样。
This happens whenever he's tense.
保尔，如果我可以的话…
Paul, if I might...
离我远点，皮博迪！
Stay away from me, Peabody!
退后！我需要牵引。
Just get back! I need traction.
你可以信任我，保尔。我是个有执照的脊椎指压治疗者。
You can trust me, Paul. I'm a licensed chiropractor.
皮博迪…
Peabody...
我觉得棒极了。
I feel great.
我感觉真的很棒！
I really feel great!
皮博迪，你真神奇的。
Peabody, you're a miracle worker.
看看我！
Look at me!
我在跳舞！
I'm dancing!
你知道吗，佩妮…
You know, Penny...
西格蒙德·弗洛伊德曾说过如果你不喜欢一个人…
Sigmund Freud says if you don't like a person...
那是因为他们让你想起了你身上让你不喜欢的地方。
it's because they remind you of something you don't like about yourself.
你知道弗洛伊德些什么？
What do you know about Sigmund Freud?
比你认为的还多。
More than you think.
哦当然。就像你知道那些东西…
Sure. Just like you know all that stuff...
说乔治华盛顿没有真的砍过一颗樱桃树。
about George Washington not really cutting down the cherry tree.
真做作。
What a crock.
但那是真的！
But it's true!
-你怎么知道？             -我就是知道！
- How do you know?        - I just know!
-你从树上读到的？                   -没有！
- Did you read it in a book?        - No!
-在电影里看到的？             -没有！
- See it in a movie?          - No!
-你那天才爸爸告诉你的？                   -没有！
- Did your brainiac dad tell you?         - No!
那你怎么知道的，谢尔曼？
So, how do you know, Sherman?
你怎么知道的？
How do you know?
他和说过的。
He told me.
谁和你说过？
Who told you?
乔治华盛顿。
George Washington.
乔治华盛顿？
George Washington?
是的。
Yeah.
骗子。
Liar.
但千万别告诉她WABAC的事。
But don't tell her about the WABAC.
他叫它“WABAC”。
He calls it the "WABAC."
那么，你们去过哪？
So, where have you gone in it?
不是“哪儿”，佩妮，应该是“什么时候”。
Not "where," Penny, "when."
好吧，聪明的小伙，什么时候？
Okay, smart guy, when?
1965年，1776年，1620年…
1965, 1776, 1620...
1492年，1215年，4
1492, 1215, 4.
-我可以回到一个小时前去吗？            -为什么？
- Can it go back to an hour ago?       - Why?
因为我可以回家，假装我病了…
Because I could take it home, pretend to be sick...
然后就可以不来参加这个差劲的晚餐派对了。
and not come to this lame dinner party.
皮博迪先生说过你不应该用WABAC…
Mr. Peabody says you should never use the WABAC...
穿越到你存在的时空。
to travel to a time when you existed.
-何以见得？           -因为那样就会有两个你了。
- How come?           - There would be two of you.
太棒了。
Yeah.
我猜这个世界会接受不了。
I guess the world's not ready for that.
哇哦。
Wow.
现在我们看完了，也许我们得回去了。
Now that we've seen it, maybe we should go back.
你开玩笑么？我们首先要去哪里？
Are you kidding? Where should we go first?
皮博迪先生说除非我长大后不然我就不可以驾驶。
Mr. Peabody says I'm not allowed to drive it till I'm older.
你都按皮博迪先生说的做？
Do you do everything Mr. Peabody says?
是啊。
Yeah.
你知道那造就了你，谢尔曼。
You know what that makes you, Sherman.
一个顺从的儿子？
An obedient son?
才不是。
Nope.
一只狗。
A dog.
好身手。
Nice control.
-看看他！             -接好了，佩蒂！
- Look at him go!     - Take it, Patty!
看着点，保尔！
Heads up, Paul!
冰在这里。走你！
Here you go. Zing!
哦，太棒了。
Oh, yeah.
嘿，看看那个。
Hey, look at that.
这太有趣了！
This is fun!
这种简谱的家庭手工调味品，我喜欢把它叫做…
This is a little homespun concoction I like to call...
“躺在沙滩上的爱因斯坦”。
"Einstein on the Beach."
真棒。
Yummy.
至我们的孩子。
To the kids.
至我们的孩子！
To the kids!
皮博迪先生。
Mr. Peabody.
-谢尔曼？         -我可以跟你说句话么？
- Sherman?        - Can I talk to you a second?
当然可以。
Of course.
抱歉。
Excuse me.
我已经和佩妮的父母聊得来了。
I've really hit it off with Penny's parents.
我想我们可以把这个夜晚打上“不合格的成功”的标签。
I think we can file this night under "Unqualified Success."
是我的话我就不会这么快给这个夜晚打标签了。
I would hold off filing it just yet.
你说的是什么意思？佩妮在哪里？
What do you mean? Where's Penny?
古埃及。
Ancient Egypt.
你们用了WABAC？
You used the WABAC?
怎么了，伙计？我们快喝完了。
What's happening, big guy? We're running low.
我马上就过去，保尔。
I'll be right there, Paul.
你们怎么可以做出这样的事？
How could you do such a thing?
她说我是个骗子…
She called me a liar...
因为我说乔治华盛顿从来没砍过一棵樱桃树。
for saying George Washington never cut down a cherry tree.
所以，你就带她去看乔治华盛顿了？
So, you took her to see George Washington?
是啊。她太喜欢了。
Yeah. She was into it.
嘿，皮老大。
Hey, Pea-buddy.
嘿。
Hey.
佩妮在哪？
Where's Penny?
-玩捉迷藏。                  -拉屎。
- Playing hide-and-seek.     - Pooping.
-拉屎。        -玩捉迷藏。
- Pooping.     - Playing hide and seek.
呃，究竟是哪个？
Well, which is it?
怎么了？
What's going on here?
对啊。怎么了？
Yeah. What's going on here?
-你对佩妮做了什么？                   -佩妮？
- What have you done with Penny?      - Penny?
佩妮？佩妮！
Penny? Penny!
-哦我的天啊！        -我们的女儿在哪里？
- Oh, my gosh!       - Where's our daughter?
这很难说，保尔。
It's hard to say, Paul.
她可以在这里，或这里，或这里，或这里…
She could be here, or here, or here, or here...
或这里。
or here.
那会定住他们。
That will hold them.
这个小花招是我在巴厘岛的乌布的里吉里从一个阁下那里学来的。
I learned that trick from a swami at the Begawan Giri in Ubud, Bali.
快走！
Let's go!
古埃及。法老之地。
Ancient Egypt. Land of the Pharaohs.
人类文明发源进步的指明灯…
A beacon of progress on the horizon of humanity...
但同时也是一个野蛮残暴的社会。
but a cruel and barbarous civilization just the same.
我希望佩妮不会受太多的苦。
I just hope Penny isn't suffering too badly.
我来捡。
I got it.
你在这干嘛？
What are you doing here?
我们来这儿带你回家。
We have come to take you home.
“告密者”在埃及语里怎么说？
What's the Egyptian word for "tattletale"?
但是那个无关紧要。穿好你的衣服，我们要回家了。
But that's beside the point. Get your clothes on, we're going home.
什么时候轮到你来当法老了？
Who died and made you Pharaoh?
现在，快来给我打扮。
Now, bring on the mani-pedi.
看见了吧，皮博迪先生？不可能的事！
See, Mr. Peabody? Impossible!
确实，但看看当一件固定的事物遇上了不可抗力时…
Indeed, but watch what happens...
会发生什么。
when an immovable object meets an irresistible force.
佩妮…
Penny...
过来这里，现在。佩妮，过来！
come here, right now. Penny, come!
我已不再是佩妮了。
I'm not Penny anymore.
现在我是哈特谢普苏特公主，珍贵的尼罗河之花。
Now, I'm Princess Hatsheput, precious flower of the Nile.
也许你确实是“珍贵的”，但如果你认为我们会把你留在这里…
"Precious," perhaps, but if you think we're going to leave you here...
你就肯定会“死在尼罗河里”。
you are most definitely in "de-Nile."
笑点在哪？
I don't get it.
现在，快过来。
Now, come along.
放开她！
Unhand her!
发生什么了，我可爱的沙漠之花？
What's the matter, my sweet little desert blossom?
这些野蛮人在骚扰你吗？
Are these barbarians bothering you?
确实是的。
As a matter of fact, they are.
鞠躬，野蛮人们。
Bow, barbarians.
如你所愿，陛下。
As you wish, Your Highness.
他是谁，皮博迪先生？
Who's that, Mr. Peabody?
他，谢尔曼，是太阳神阿蒙德化身…
That, Sherman, is the living image of Amun...
阿肯那顿之子，这个新王国的第18个国王…
son of Akhenaten, lord of the 18th Dynasty of the New Kingdom...
图坦卡蒙王。
King Tutankhamun.
也被称为“图特王”。
Otherwise known as "King Tut."
我男朋友。
My boyfriend.
图特王是你男朋友？
King Tut is your boyfriend?
你想要把他们的皮剥下来，敷上一层蜂蜜…
Would you like me to have them skinned, covered with honey...
然后放进火蚁坑里吗？
and laid in a pit of fire ants?
你会为了我这么做吗？
You would do that for me?
任何事，我的沙漠之花。这是我给你的结婚礼物。
Anything, my desert flower. Consider it a wedding gift.
什么？你不能嫁给这个人！
What? You can't marry this guy!
为什么不行？
Why not?
首先，他的名字和“屁股”谐音。
For one, his name rhymes with "butt."
我才不管。我要拥有一个大大的隆重的埃及式婚礼。
I don't care. I'm gonna have a big, fat, Egyptian wedding.
给你透露一下，图特王很年轻的时候就死了。
Spoiler alert, King Tut dies young.
你确定你已经考虑过了吗？
Are you sure you've thought this through?
相信我，我都想通了。我要得到一切东西。
Trust me, I've thought it through. I'm getting everything.
皇家天文学家刚刚做了观测…
The royal astronomers have decreed...
明天傍晚是举行婚礼的好时辰。
the wedding must take place tomorrow at dawn.
他是谁？
Who is he?
-他是艾。           -他是你？
- He is Ay.         - He is you?
我是艾。大维齐尔。
I am Ay. The Grand Vizier.
-是的，那就是他的名字。        -哦。
- Yeah, that's his name.       - Oh.
大维齐尔宰相，你可不可以准确地给这位珍贵的公主…
Grand Vizier, would you mind telling the precious princess, here...
描述一下嫁给这位年轻的法老意味着什么。
precisely what it means to marry the young Pharaoh.
荣幸之至。
Gladly.
那意味着她将通过那神圣的仪式取出她的内脏对她进行木乃伊化…
It means she will be bound to him in eternity...
让她来世也属于他…
through the sacred ceremonies of disembowelment and mummification...
就像圣书上描述的那样。
as described in the holy texts.
等一等。
Hold up a second.
有谁可以跟我说更清楚一点？
Can you walk me through that, somebody?
佩妮，他的意思是，当我死的时候，他们也会把你杀死。
What he means, Penny, is that when I die they'll kill you, too.
然后把你的器官挖出来，塞进卡诺皮克坛子里…
And then they'll rip out your organs, stuff them in canopic jars...
然后把剩下的你做成木乃伊。
and then mummify whatever is left.
好的，我现在已经了解了。
Okay, I'm seeing this now.
谢谢你。现在我要和他们一起走了。
Thank you. I'm going to go with them.
现在已经没有回头路了。
There's no turning back now.
往宫殿！
To the palace!
开始准备婚礼！
Let the wedding preparations begin!
皮博迪先生！谢尔曼！
Mr. Peabody! Sherman!
帮帮我！
Do something!
别担心，佩妮！
Don't worry, Penny!
我们会救你的！
We'll save you!
嘿，等等！你们不能就这样…
Hey, wait! You can't just...
把我们丢在这。
leave us here.
皮博迪先生？
Mr. Peabody?
怎么了，谢尔曼？
Yes, Sherman?
我可以牵你的手吗？
Can I hold your hand?
当然可以。
Of course you can.
哦，你的手好冷啊，皮博迪先生。
Boy, your hand is cold, Mr. Peabody.
-谢尔曼？        -怎么了？
- Sherman?       - Yeah?
那不是我的手。
That's not my hand.
那是一只断臂。
That's disarming.
现在，让我们找条路出去吧。
Now, to find a way out of here.
看看周围，谢尔曼。
Look around, Sherman.
这些古墓布满了象形文字…
These tombs are lined with hieroglyphics...
它们被用来在法老们的灵魂转世的途中帮助他们。
designed to assist the pharaohs' souls in their journey to the afterlife.
这些文字也许也可以帮助我们。
And they may assist us as well.
这幅画描述了阿努比斯之神驾驶着拉神的船去冥界。
This depicts the god Anubis sailing the boat of Ra to the underworld.
这意味着拉神的船是我们逃出这里的关键。
It appears the boats of Ra are the key to our escape.
我们必须及时找到它们来阻止婚礼。
We must find them in time to stop the wedding.
呃，如果你问我的话，我们应该让她嫁给那个家伙。
Well, if you ask me, we should let her marry that guy.
他们挺配得上对方的。
They deserve each other.
怎么了，谢尔曼？
What's that, Sherman?
图特？别贫了。
Tut? Give me a break.
秃顶，穿着衬衫，还化妆。
Bald, wears a skirt, and makeup.
按照我的理解，谢尔曼，我认为你在吃醋。
If I didn't know any better, Sherman, I would say you were jealous.
吃醋？吃谁的醋？
Jealous? Of what?
图特对佩妮的喜爱，不是吗？
Tut's affection for Penny, of course.
你以为我喜欢佩妮？
You think I like Penny?
别贫了！
Give me a break!
这不比我想牵她的手，或者去公园
It's not like I want to hold her hand, or go to the park...
或者看着她梳头发。
or watch her while she's brushing her hair.
或者别的任何事。
Or anything.
快点，谢尔曼。
Quickly, Sherman.
小心点，谢尔曼。
Careful, Sherman.
这是个诱杀装置。
It's a booby trap.
-有什么好笑的？         -你刚刚说“傻瓜”。
- What's so funny?      - You said "booby."
只要踏错一步我们就完了。
One wrong step and we're done for.
“拉神…
"The boat...
“的船直向
"of Ra sails straight...
“白天。
"to day.
“搭上了错误的船…
"Take the wrong boat...
“就会付出代价。
man will pay."
好了，谢尔曼，轮到你了。
All right, Sherman, now it's your turn.
像我完全一样地解开这个谜底。
Do the puzzle exactly as I did.
好好想，一次一格。
Think it through, one step at a time.
拉神的船直向…
The boat of Ra sails straight...
玩。
play.
我的意思是，“还”。
I mean, "pay."
哦，天哪。
Oh, my.
哦哦。
Uh-oh.
快跑！
Run!
拉神的船！
The boats of Ra!
一只船可以带我们离开这里，另一只则会…
One boat is the way out, the other will send us...
带我们陷入黑暗和死亡。
plunging into darkness and certain death.
什么？
What?
谢尔曼，去船上。
Sherman, get in the boat.
当我把这些方块组合起来时，船将会移动得很快。
As soon as I move these blocks together, it's going to move very fast.
-哪一只船，皮博迪先生？         -什么？
- Which boat, Mr. Peabody?      - What?
哪一只船不是“带我们陷入黑暗和死亡”的船？
Which boat is the "not-certain-death-plunge" boat?
那一只！
That one!
我们做到了，谢尔曼！
We did it, Sherman!
谢尔曼？
Sherman?
皮博迪先生！
Mr. Peabody!
你在那里干嘛？
What are you doing over there?
我以为你指的是这艘船！
I thought you pointed to this one!
谢尔曼？谢尔曼？
Sherman? Sherman?
你还好吗？
Are you all right?
我还行。
I'm good.
太阳之神，拉神…
The sun god, Ra...
要求我们开始这场神圣的庆典！
commands us to begin the sacred ceremony!
把刀刃带上前来准备血誓。
Bring forth the blade for the blood oath.
当刀锋在这场神圣的仪式上与血肉相遇…
Where blade meets flesh in this sacred rite...
我们以此贡品…
we pay tribute...
献给太阳之神，拉神！
to the sun god, Ra!
等等！
Wait!
阿努比斯！
Anubis!
死亡之神！
The god of death!
婚礼不可以继续。
The wedding must not continue.
为什么，阿努比斯，为什么？
Why, Anubis, why?
瘟疫，瘟疫！
Plagues. Plagues!
如果这门婚事定下来了…
If this marriage pact is sealed...
我会在这片大地降下难以数计的瘟疫。
I will shower down upon the land uncountable plagues.
靠，又是瘟疫！
Oy, again with the plagues!
我干嘛要搬到埃及来？
Why did I ever move to Egypt?
但是，阿努比斯，太阳之神，拉神，曾宣布…
But, Anubis, the sun god, Ra, has decreed...
这个女孩定要成为这个男孩的王妃。
that this girl is to be the boy-king's wife.
那就有趣了。
That's so funny.
我那天在和拉神聊天时…
I was talking to the sun god, Ra, just the other day...
他跟我说他改主意了。
and he told me he changed his mind.
真的？
Really?
所以我们在冥界都叫他“成天改主意的拉神”。
Old "Flip-Flop Ra," we call him here in the underworld.
但现在太迟了。我们已经付了那么多钱了。
But it's too late. We've already paid for the catering.
太糟了！你们就要失去我对你们的保佑了。
Too bad! You're going to lose your deposit.
再来点烟，谢尔曼。这个阿努比斯之狗诡计起作用了。
More smoke, Sherman. This canine subterfuge is working.
交出那个女孩…
Deliver the girl...
把她放在城门，留她在那里…
to the gates of the city, and leave her there...
让神可以重新得到她。
where the gods will retrieve her forthwith.
只有这样做才可以让这片土地避免瘟疫。
Only in this manner may the plagues upon this land be avoided.
放那个女孩走！
The girl must go!
阿努比斯发话了！
Anubis has spoken!
把那个女孩带去城门！
Take this girl to the gates!
阿努比斯，你听起来不太好。
Anubis, you sound unwell.
呃，我最近总觉得人有点不舒服…
Well, I have been feeling a little under the weather...
但我现在感觉好多了。
but I'm feeling much better now.
谢谢。
Thank you.
佩妮，谢尔曼，快点！
Penny, Sherman, quickly.
过来，佩妮。
Come on, Penny.
谢尔曼！
Sherman!
逃跑的新娘！
Runaway bride!
把他们拦下，你们这些蠢货！
Stop them, you fools!
佩妮，谢尔曼，爬上去。
Penny, Sherman, climb aboard.
他们就要跑掉了！
They're getting away!
我捡到了。
I got it.
我们逃出来了。
We made it.
-我们接下来要去哪，皮博迪先生？           -回家。
- Where do we go next, Mr. Peabody?       - Home.
我们一定要在佩妮的父母发现她失踪前…
We've got to get back to the dinner party...
回到派对上。
before Penny's parents realize she's missing.
我们不需要提到整个…
We don't have to mention the whole...
图特王的婚事什么的，对不？
King Tut wedding thing, right?
是的。
Certainly not.
无论如何，就我看来，古埃及的人都太早结婚了。
Anyway, as far as I'm concerned, they get married too young in Ancient Egypt.
或者我可能只是老“吉萨”。
Or, perhaps, I'm just some old "Giza."
警告。
Warning.
WABAC能量供应不足。
WABAC power supply insufficient.
正在充电。警告。
Charge now. Warning.
怎么了，皮博迪先生？
What's the matter, Mr. Peabody?
频繁地撕开宇宙裂缝榨干了我们的能源供应。
All this zipping about the cosmos has drained our power supply.
我们将不得不进行计划外的停止。
We're going to have to make an unscheduled stop.
走运的是…
As luck would have it...
我们刚刚好有足够的能源使我们到达文艺复兴时期。
we have just enough power to make it to the Renaissance.
我甚至没法区别出我的左右脑了！
I can't even tell my left brain from my right anymore!
我已经告诉你多少次了，蒙娜丽莎？
How many times I got to tell you, Mona Lisa?
蒙娜丽莎？
Mona Lisa?
如果你不笑的话…
I can't paint the picture...
我就没法画！
until you smile!
莱昂纳多，告诉我一件值得让我微笑的事。
Leonardo, tell me one thing I have to smile about.
阳光，意大利面。
The sunshine, the pasta.
所有这些让意大利成为游览景点的都值得你微笑！
All the things that make Italy such a popular tourist destination!
但这些东西我都没见过，莱昂纳多！
But I have not seen any of them, Leonardo!
因为我整天都坐在我的abbondanza上！
Because I'm sitting here all day on my abbondanza!
我认为那个词在意大利语里不是“椅子”的意思。
I don't think that means "chair" in Italian.
皮博迪，我的老朋友。
Peabody, my old friend.
多么欢迎的来扰！
What a welcome interruption!
相信我，这个女的快让我变傻了。
Believe you me, this woman is making me nuts.
那么，近来如何？
So, how you been?
真高兴见到你。你想做什么？
Good to see you. What do you want?
我们非常急着回家，但是WABAC需要一个跃进式启动…
We're in a desperate hurry to get home, but the WABAC needs a jump start...
然后我们就想，有谁可以比莱昂纳多·达·芬奇做得更好帮我们回家？
and we thought, who better than Leonardo da Vinci to help us on our way?
皮博迪，我很愿意帮助你，但是你来的真不是时候。
Peabody, I would love to help you, but you come at a very bad time.
我不知道要怎么应付这个疯女人。
I don't know what I'm going to do with this crazy woman.
-知道我什么意思了吧？         -有什么难题吗？
- You see what I mean?        - What seems to be the problem?
“有什么麻烦吗？”
"What is the problem?"
这幅画我都快画完了，但是她就是不肯笑。
I am halfway done with the painting, she won't even smile.
好的。我笑给你看。
Fine. I smile.
不！那个笑容是假的！
No! That's a fake smile!
每个人都看得出来！
Everybody knows that!
你为什么不真的笑出来？
Why don't you make it a real smile?
你干嘛不说些有趣的东西？
Why don't you say something funny?
我只顾画画。
I paint the paintings.
我会造机器。
I make the machines.
我不会讲笑话！
I don't tell the jokes!
也许，我可以帮到你。你瞧…
Perhaps, I can be of assistance. You see...
幽默并不与科学定律互相排斥。
humor is not immune to the laws of science.
运用算法，我们就可以推断出什么是广义上的“有趣”…
Using algorithms, we can extrapolate what is universally considered "funny"...
接着就用科学的方法准确写出可以制造笑声的方程式。
thus producing a formula that is scientifically certain to cause laughter.
举一个恰当的例子，屁股着地的摔倒。
Case in point, the pratfall.
每个人都被我逗笑了么？
Is everyone amused?
数据看起来是如此清楚。
The data was so clear.
别担心，皮博迪先生。
Don't worry, Mr. Peabody.
-让我来！        -谢尔曼…
- I got it!      - Sherman...
保持住那个微笑！
Hold that smile!
就是那样！别动！别动！
Hold it right there! No move! No move!
莱昂，如果我的计算式正确的话…
Well, Leo, if my calculations are correct...
我们的机器应该要产生足够的离心力…
this machine of ours should generate enough centrifugal force...
来带我们回家。
to send us home.
我这有一块零件需要用锤子锤好。
I got one last piece I gotta pound in place.
谢尔曼，为什么不把那只锤子拿给达芬奇先生呢？
Sherman, why don't you fetch the hammer for Mr. Da Vinci?
好的，皮博迪先生。
Okay, Mr. Peabody.
皮博迪先生！
Mr. Peabody!
做得好，谢尔曼。
Well done, Sherman.
但是，皮博迪先生！
But, Mr. Peabody!
你真会帮忙。
Very helpful.
谢尔曼！
Sherman!
是的，皮博迪先生？
Yes, Mr. Peabody?
那支锤子。
The hammer.
达芬奇。
Da Vinci.
好的，皮博迪先生。
Okay, Mr. Peabody.
我拿来给你了，达芬奇先生。
Here you go, Mr. Da Vinci.
你还需要帮忙吗？
Do you need any help?
不，不。那样就好。
No, no. That's quite all right.
谢谢。
Thank you.
谢尔曼。
Sherman.
咋们一起看探险。
Let's go. Let's go explore.
呃，我应该在这儿和皮博迪先生一起干活的。
Well, I'm supposed to be having father-son time with Mr. Peabody.
你就不更想和我一起玩？
Wouldn't you rather have fun with me?
好吧。
Okay.
谢尔曼…
Sherman...
你想去哪里？
where are you going?
探险。
Exploring.
但我们需要你的帮助。
But we need your help.
不，我们不需要！我的意思是，我们搞得掂。
No, we don't! I mean, we can manage.
怎样都行。
Somehow.
他是个小男孩，皮博迪。
He's a boy, Peabody.
让他玩去吧。让他走。
Let him have his fun. Let him go.
谢谢，皮博迪先生！
Thanks, Mr. Peabody!
他在长大，皮博迪。
He's growing up, Peabody.
就像一只将要离开巢穴的小鸟。
Like a baby bird leaving the nest.
那不美好吗？
Isn't it wonderful?
这儿就像博物馆。
It's like a museum.
这儿就像玩具店。
It's like a toy store.
哇哦。
Wow.
看看这个。
Check this out.
这是世界最大的飞机模型。
It's the world's biggest model airplane.
这不是飞机模型，佩妮。这是个飞机原型。
It's not a model, Penny. It's a prototype.
我们也许不应该去碰它。
And we should probably just leave that alone.
好的。
Okay.
如果我们可以驾驶它的话那不是很酷吗？
But wouldn't it be cool if we could fly it?
我认为皮博士先生不会喜欢这样的。
I don't think Mr. Peabody would like that.
可是，皮博迪先生不在这里。
Well, Mr. Peabody isn't here.
告诉我怎么让它飞起来就好了。
Just tell me how it works.
求你了。
Please?
知道一下就好。
For learning.
好吧。
Okay.
这个像弓弩的装置提供了飞行器起飞的推力。
The thrust comes from this kind of crossbow doohickey here.
接着飞行器沿着这个轨道发射出去直到风把机翼托起来。
Then it shoots along the track until the wind catches the wings.
可是要怎样发射呢？
But how does it go?
应该怎么起飞？
How do you take off?
你只要拉那个把手就好了。
You just pull down that lever.
这支吗？
This one?
哦天哪。
Oh, boy.
这太疯狂了！
This is crazy!
不，这不疯狂，谢尔曼！这很好玩！
No, it's not Sherman. It's fun!
我们要死在这里了！
We're gonna die!
别像个胆小鬼似的，快嗨起来吧！
Stop being such a party pooper and enjoy it!
没什么事比优雅的方程式…
Nothing is as beautiful as an elegant equation...
转化为完美的工程那样美妙了。
translated into perfect engineering.
为什么小孩就不能这样简单？
Why can't children be so simple?
因为小孩不是机器，谢尔曼。
Because children are not machines, Peabody.
相信我，我试过造一个小孩。
Believe me, I tried to build one.
那太可怕了。
It was creepy.
给你，谢尔曼！你来控制。
Here, Sherman! You fly it!
但我不想控制！
But I don't want to fly!
你当然想。这很有趣的！
Sure you do. It'll be fun!
不，说真的，佩妮，我真的不想！
No, seriously, Penny, I don't want to!
我要放手了。一…
I'm letting go. One...
别放手！
Don't let go!
二…
Two...
-不！         -三！
- No!         - Three!
佩妮，快让它飞起来！
Penny, fly the plane!
不，谢尔曼！
No, Sherman!
-你必须救我们！                      -但我做不到！
- You're going to have to save us!   - But I can't do it!
我是认真的，佩妮。我不知道怎么飞！
I'm serious, Penny. I don't know how to fly!
你可以的！我知道你一定行的！
You can do it! I know you can!
来吧，谢尔曼。
Come on, Sherman.
飞起来！
Fly!
看见了吧？你做到了，谢尔曼。
See? You got this, Sherman.
你是对的。我做到了。
You're right. I have got this.
又是达芬奇在飞！
Da Vinci's at it again!
你见过他造的那个孩子吗？
You ever see that child he made?
太惊悚了。
So creepy.
爸爸。妈妈。
Papa. Mama.
我这上面干完了，莱昂纳多。
All done up here, Leonardo.
我这下面也干完了。
And I am all done down here.
这太美了，不是吗？
It is beautiful, isn't it?
每个零件都在自身的位置准确地做它该做的事。
Every piece in its place doing precisely what it's supposed to do.
看，皮博迪！
Look, Peabody!
那是我的飞行…
It's my flying mach...
我的飞行器！
My flying machine?
谢尔曼。
Sherman.
谢尔曼？
Sherman?
谢尔曼，你在上面干嘛？
Sherman, what are you doing up there?
我在飞！
I'm flying!
但是，谢尔曼，你不知道怎样飞！
But, Sherman, you don't know how to fly!
我不知道？
I don't?
是的！
No!
快转弯！
Turn!
快转弯，谢尔曼！
Turn, Sherman!
倾斜！
Lean!
谢尔曼？
Sherman?
谢尔曼！你还好吗？
Sherman! Are you okay?
刚才那个太赞了！
That was pretty fantastic!
难以置信！
I can't believe it!
我的飞行器！它飞起来了！
My flying machine! It's work!
谢尔曼！你是第一个飞起来的人！
Sherman! You are the first flying man!
你应该很自豪，皮博迪。
You should be very proud, Peabody.
非常，非常自豪！
Very, very proud!
我可没有觉得“自豪”。
"Proud" doesn't begin to describe it.
莱昂纳多，请你发动那个装置好吗？
Leonardo, will you please fire up the mechanism?
爸爸。妈妈。
Papa. Mama.
蒙娜！
Mona!
爸爸。妈妈。
Papa. Mama.
那个孩子！
The kid!
很抱歉我弄坏了那个飞行器，皮博迪先生。
I'm sorry I broke the plane, Mr. Peabody.
是的，你应该觉得抱歉。你甚至可能会摔死。
Well, you should be. You could have been killed.
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
谢尔曼刚刚在开飞机。他太棒了！
Sherman flew a plane. He was amazing!
谢尔曼毁掉了一件无价的历史文物。
Sherman destroyed a priceless historical artifact.
我才不管那是什么。你应该觉得高兴。
Whatever. You should be happy.
毕竟那说明了谢尔曼不是一个一无是处的失败者。
It turns out Sherman is not a complete and total loser, after all.
是的，皮博迪先生。
Yeah, Mr. Peabody.
毕竟那说明了我不是一个一无是处的失败者。
It turns out I'm not a complete and total loser, after all.
彼得逊女士…
Ms. Peterson...
别再把我的孩子教成一个小混混。
stop turning my son into a hooligan.
他是个小混混又不是我的错。
It's not my fault he's a hooligan.
就是，我是个小混混又不是她的错。
Yeah, it's not her fault I'm a hooligan.
可那显然也不是我的错！
Well, it's certainly not my fault!
我花了七年时间培养了谢尔曼良好的判断力。
I've spent the last seven years teaching Sherman good judgment.
如果你真是个好家长…
If you're such a great parent...
那为什么古宁恩女士要把他从你身边带走？
why is Ms. Grunion trying to take Sherman away from you?
那是真的吗？
Is that true?
有人要把我从你身边带走？
Is someone gonna take me away from you?
不，谢尔曼，我是不会让它发生的。
No, Sherman, I'll never let that happen.
请相信我。
You just need to trust me.
哦，天啊，黑洞！
Oh, dear, a black hole!
发生了什么事？
What's happening?
如果我不能把我们拉出这里…
If I can't pull us out of here...
我们就会在黑洞表面被压成碎片。
we're going to be smashed to smithereens on the event horizon.
这台机器已经没有足够的动力来抵抗这么强大的引力了！
There's not enough power to resist the gravitational pull!
我要启动倒退助推器来帮我们转向。
I've got to divert everything to the reverse thrusters.
你为什么不告诉我？
Why didn't you tell me?
告诉你什么？
Tell you what?
为什么不告诉我古宁恩夫人要把我从你身边带走？
Why didn't you tell me Ms. Grunion was trying to take me away from you?
那不是你该担心的事情。
It's not your job to worry about these things.
你只是认为我没法解决这件事。
You just didn't think I could handle it.
我们等会再来讨论这个问题。现在，坐下。
We'll discuss it later. Now, sit down.
我现在就想讨论这个问题！
I don't want to discuss it later!
谢尔曼，坐下！
Sherman, sit!
你不可以和我这样说话。
You can't talk to me like that.
-我才不是一只狗。    -你说什么？
- I'm not a dog.     - What did you say?
我说，我才不是一只狗！
I said, I'm not a dog!
你说得没错，谢尔曼，你不是。
You're right, Sherman, you're not.
你只是个非常坏的男孩！
You're just a very bad boy!
倒计时，10…
T-minus 10...
九，八…
Nine, eight...
七…
Seven...
六…
Six...
五…
Five...
四，三…
Four, three...
二…
Two...
一。
One.
谢尔曼？
Sherman?
佩妮？
Penny?
谢尔曼，你还好吗？
Sherman, are you okay?
谢尔曼？
Sherman?
他走了。
He's gone.
我们在哪儿？
Where are we, anyway?
哦，不。
Oh, no.
我们在历史上最残忍的冲突事件之一的边缘…
We're on the brink of one of history's most ferocious conflicts...
送快递的。
Delivery.
现在觉得如何，希腊英雄？
How are we doing, heroes of Greece?
觉得好吗？
Feeling good?
觉得无所不能？
Feeling strong?
好的，现在来热热身子！
Okay, let's get warmed up!
我们并不想从那里面抢点什么东西出来。
We don't want to pull something out there.
想一想阿基里斯的下场。
Remember what happened to Achilles.
他那脚后跟的事。
That whole thing with his heel.
看起来很棒，狄俄墨德斯（希腊著名的大英雄，阿尔戈斯的国王）。
Looking good, Diomedes.
墨涅拉俄斯（斯巴达之王），好样的！
Menelaus, my man!
好样的。
My man.
你准备好要上战场了吗，谢尔曼纳斯？
Are you ready to get on the field, Shermanus?
是的，阿加门农先生（希腊军统帅）。
Sure thing, Mr. Agamemnon.
真可爱。
That's cute.
奥德修斯（曾指挥特洛伊战争），你带来了什么新消息？
Odysseus, what news do you bring?
有人给我们送来了这个。
Someone left this for us.
一个礼物。真好。
A present. Nice.
看起来就像我们的木马一样。
It looks just like our horse.
要我带进来吗？
Should I bring it inside?
不然的话就太粗鲁了。
It would be rude not to.
我可没看见那只狗！
I did not see that coming!
老天啊，这什么味？
Jeez Louise, what is that smell?
这是胜利的味道！
That is the smell of victory.
耶！胜利！
Yeah! Victory!
大家好，雅典，斯巴达，底比斯的壮士们。
Greetings, men of Athens, Sparta and Thebes.
皮博迪在此。
Peabody, here.
我是为谢尔曼而来。
I've come for Sherman.
-你认识这个家伙吗？        -我曾认为我认识…
- Do you know this guy?    - I thought I did...
但现在我不太肯定。
but now I'm not so sure.
那么他就是个间谍！杀了他！
Then he must be a spy. Kill him!
不！不！
No! No!
他是我爸。
He's my dad.
你爸？
Your dad?
他们父子是收养关系。
It's an adoptive relationship.
谢谢你这么照顾我的孩子，阿加门农先生…
Thank you for taking such good care of my son, Agamemnon...
但现在他应该回家了。
but it's time for him to come home.
对不起，皮博迪先生，我已经加入了希腊军队。
Sorry, Mr. Peabody, I've joined the Greek army.
谢尔曼已经是我们中的一员了。
Shermanus is one of us now.
-他是我们的兄弟。    -我是他的兄弟。
- He's a brother.    - I'm his brother.
他是我儿子。
He's my son.
-他起了誓。           -我了起誓。
- He took an oath.    - I took an oath.
他才七岁！
He's seven!
加半年！
And a half!
所有的孩子应该向他们的父亲证明自己。
All sons must prove themselves to their fathers.
今天…
Today...
谢尔曼纳斯将在战场上证明自己。
Shermanus will prove himself on the field of battle.
但他还是个孩子。
But he's only a child.
你爸也许认为你还没准备好成为一个男人，谢尔曼纳斯…
Your dad may not think you're ready to become a man, Shermanus...
但我们都这么认为。
but we do.
-就是！           -是的，皮博迪先生。
- Yeah!           - Yeah, Mr. Peabody.
现在我就来给你看看我可以对付的事情。
Now, I'll show you what I can handle.
事实上，有很多英雄都有类似的烦恼。
FYI, a lot of heroes have father issues.
我的老爸是个弥诺陶洛斯（人身牛头怪物）。
My old man is a minotaur.
半人，半牛，大家议论纷纷。
Half man, half bull, all judgment.
阿贾克斯，在这儿，世界上最强壮的人…
Ajax, here, strongest guy in the world...
但他的父亲对他真实的梦想是成为歌唱家这件事一直无法接受。
but his father never accepted that his real dream was to sing.
我想加入希腊合唱团。
I wanted to be in the Greek chorus.
哦对了，还有俄狄浦斯…
Yeah, and don't even get me started about Oedipus.
这么说吧，你会一点都不想去他家度假的。
Let's just say that you do not want to be at his house over the holidays.
这很尴尬。
It's awkward.
谢尔曼，我觉得你应该好好想想。
Sherman, I'm concerned you haven't thought this through.
这是战争。你知道那将会发生什么吗？
This is war. Do you realize what's about to happen?
我来告诉你会发生什么。
I'll tell you what's gonna happen.
我们会毁掉他们的家园！
We're gonna destroy their houses!
推倒他们的神庙！
Pull down their temples!
用特洛伊人的鲜血让城市里的街道…
And make the streets of the city run red...
染成红色！
with Trojan blood!
太棒了！
Yeah!
血！血！血！
Blood! Blood! Blood!
我数三下！一！
Zeus on three! One!
谢尔曼，我绝对禁止你参加特洛伊战争。
Sherman, I absolutely forbid you to fight in the Trojan War.
这不公平！我的所有朋友都将参加。
It's not fair! All my friends are fighting in the Trojan War.
-二！          -谢尔曼，这很危险。
- Two!         - Sherman, it's dangerous.
我戴着头盔。
I'm wearing a helmet.
-三！        -你别走！
- Three!     - You're not going!
我偏要走。
Yes, I am.
上啊！
Zeus!
吃我一剑，你们这些特洛伊狗！
Eat my bronze, you Trojan dogs!
Eat my bronze, you Trojan dog!
恩，好险啊。
Well, that's cutting it close.
这就是我叫你要跟紧我的原因，谢尔曼。
This is why I ask you to obey me, Sherman.
因为我是你的父亲，我的工作就是保护你的安全。
Because I'm your father, and it's my job to keep you safe.
但你确定古宁恩夫人不会把我从你身边带走？
But are you sure Ms. Grunion won't take me away?
只要我还在你身边就不会。
Not as long as I'm around.
皮博迪先生！
Mr. Peabody!
救命！
Help me!
佩妮！
Penny!
闻闻我的胜利！
Smell my victory!
闻一下！
Smell it!
嘿！那是我的座驾！
Hey! That's my ride!
皮博迪先生…
Mr. Peabody...
快点！
hurry!
我拿走了。
I'll take that.
你做到了，谢尔曼！
You did it, Sherman!
皮博迪先生干的。
Mr. Peabody helped.
现在，咱们去WABAC那里吧，回家，给佩妮的父母解除催眠…
Now, let's get to the WABAC, go home, un-hypnotize Penny's parents...
完成晚餐派对，吃我的火焰冰激凌…
finish that dinner party, eat my Baked Alaska...
顺便把古宁恩夫人的裤子一起迷倒…
charm the pants off Ms. Grunion...
然后确保这件事从没发生过。
and make sure none of this ever happens in the first place.
听起来很棒。
Sounds good.
我来了。
I'm in.
谢尔曼！
Sherman!
-佩妮！         -谢尔曼，不！
- Penny!        - Sherman, no!
皮博迪先生…
Mr. Peabody...
皮博迪先生？
Mr. Peabody?
皮博迪先生！
Mr. Peabody!
爸爸！
Dad!
皮博迪先生！我应该怎么办？我应该怎么办？
Mr. Peabody! What should I do? What should I do?
你什么都做不了，谢尔曼。
There's nothing you can do, Sherman.
我只想回家。
I just want to go home.
家。
Home.
就是那个了。
That's it.
我有主意了。
I got an idea.
快点！
Come on!
我们要去哪？
Where are we gonna go?
我们回家。
We're going home.
只有一个人可以帮助我们…
There's only one person who can help us...
那就是皮博迪先生。
and that's Mr. Peabody.
你在说什么？这怎么可能？
What are you talking about? How is that even possible?
我们有时光机器，佩妮！
We've got a time machine, Penny!
我们可以设定它回到皮博迪先生还在家的时候。
I can set it so that we'll get home when Mr. Peabody is still there.
但我认为你不应该回到你存在的时空。
But I thought you're not supposed to go back to a time when you existed.
我们还有什么选择？
What choice do we have?
错误，你正试着要回到你所存在的时空。
Error. You are attempting to travel to an era in which you exist.
这可能会改变宇宙时空的结构。
This could alter the fabric of space-time.
错误。错误。
Error. Error.
抓紧了！
Hang on!
这太有趣了！！
This is fun!
这种简谱的家庭手工调味品，我喜欢把它叫做…
This is a little homespun concoction I like to call...
“躺在沙滩上的爱因斯坦”。
"Einstein on the Beach."
真棒。
Yummy.
至我们的孩子。
To the kids.
至我们的孩子！
To the kids!
皮博迪先生。
Mr. Peabody.
谢尔曼？佩妮？
Sherman? Penny?
我们可以跟你说句话么？
Can we talk to you a second?
当然可以。
Of course.
抱歉。
Excuse me.
我已经和佩妮的父母聊得来了。
I've really hit it off with your parents.
我想我们可以把这个夜晚打上“不合格的成功”的标签。
I think we can file this night under "Unqualified Success."
是我的话我就不会这么快给这个夜晚打标签了。
I'd hold off filing it just yet.
你说的是什么意思？
What do you mean?
为什么你们穿得像个古希腊人？
Why are you two dressed like ancient Greeks?
-你们用了WABAC!             -是的。
- You used the WABAC!       - I did.
我知道，那很糟糕！
I know, it's terrible!
但是为什么？
But why?
佩妮和我因为乔治华盛顿的事吵了起来。
Penny and I got into an argument about George Washington.
所以，我就让他带我去看了WABAC。
So, I made him show me the WABAC.
-我就把她落在古埃及了。                -我还和图特王订婚了。
- And I lost her in ancient Egypt.     - And I got engaged to King Tut.
-所以我就回来找你了。                 -然后机器没燃料了。
- So, I came back and got you.        - Then we ran out of gas.
-在佛罗伦萨。      -我们撞上了黑洞。
- In Florence.     - Went into a black hole.
然后你死在了古特洛伊。
And then you died in ancient Troy.
我死了？我才不信呢。
Died? I have a hard time believing that.
那是真的！
It's true!
但现在你在这里，一切都会好起来的。
But now you're here, and everything's gonna be okay.
我告诉过你你不应该回到你存在的时空来。
I told you never to come back to a time when you existed...
因为那样的话就会有两个你了！
because there would be two of you!
是啊，但另外一个我现在在古埃及。
Yeah, but the other one of me is in ancient Egypt.
你是谁？
Who are you?
他是你，但是是从别的时空来的。
He's you, but from another timeline.
但是我以为你说过不要回到你存在的时空来。
But I thought you said never to come back to a time when you existed.
-完全正确！     -我知道。
- Exactly!    - I know.
但我应该怎么办？皮博迪先生死在了古特洛伊。
But what was I supposed to do? Mr. Peabody died in ancient Troy.
死了？
Died?
我才不信呢。
I have a hard time believing that.
谢谢。
Thank you.
我们应该怎么办？
What are we going to do?
首先，两个谢尔曼都不可以在这里。
For starters, both Shermans can't stay here.
为什么？我们可以睡上下铺。
Why? We could get bunk beds.
我也在想这个。
I was thinking the same thing.
这好奇怪。就像我们是双胞胎一样！
That's so weird. It's like we're twins!
我也在想那个！
I was thinking that, too!
看见了吧？我们不可以把两个谢尔曼留在同一个时空。
You see? We can't have two Shermans in the same timeline.
这给宇宙时空施加了太多的张力。
It puts too much strain on the space-time continuum.
该怎么办？彼得逊一家不可以知道这件事。
What to do? The Petersons can't know any of this.
嘿，皮老大。
Hey, Pea-buddy.
嘿。
Hey.
还好吗？
How's it going?
佩蒂和我吃得很开心。
Patty and I are working up an appetite.
你厨房里的味道真是好闻啊。
The smells coming from your kitchen are yummy!
特别是那个火焰冰激凌。
Especially that Baked Alaska.
那么，你们在干什么呢？
So, what's going on here?
是啊，干嘛穿成这样？
Yeah, what's with the getups?
古罗马长袍派对！
Toga party!
古罗马长袍派对？
Toga party?
是啊，古罗马长袍派对！
Yes, it is a toga party!
那么，晚餐呢？
Well, what about dinner?
我饿死了。
I'm starving.
为什么不去餐厅…
Why don't we head into the dining room...
然后去大吃特吃一顿你一直在说的鹌鹑？
and tuck into those quails you've been yakking about?
-不！     -为什么不行？
- No!     - Why not?
因为呆在这里很有趣！
Because it's so fun right here!
古宁恩夫人！
Ms. Grunion!
多么棒啊！
How delightful.
我们在这儿很开心…
We were having such a good time...
我差点忘了你会来了。
I almost forgot you were coming.
干嘛不加入我们呢？
Why don't you join the party?
我来这儿不是来参加派对的。我在这儿是来做调查的。
I'm not here for a party. I'm here for the investigation.
行。你干嘛不在这开始你的调查呢？
Good. Why don't you start investigating over here?
或者这里，或者这里，或者这里…
Or here, or here, or here...
别乱挥你的手！
Stop waving your hands around!
谢尔曼？
Sherman?
等一下！那是不是…
Wait! Is that...?
谢尔曼！
Sherman!
两个谢尔曼？这是怎么了，皮博迪？
Dos Shermanos? What's going on here, Peabody?
每个人都别动！
Nobody move!
谢尔曼，我要在你碰到自己之前把你带走。
Sherman, I've got to get you out of here before you touch yourself.
皮博迪先生！你没死！
Mr. Peabody! You didn't die!
我当然没死。
Of course I didn't die.
谢谢。
Thank you.
嘿。你是怎么回来的？
Hey. How did you get back?
其实，在经过几次失败的尝试之后…
Well, after a few failed experiments...
我把骨头，石头，还有牦牛的脂肪…
I hit upon a combination of bones, stone and yak fat...
组合起来造了个原始版的WABAC。
and constructed a rudimentary WABAC.
你知道老话说得好…
You know what they say...
“如果一开始你没有成功，那就再试一次。”
"If at first you don't succeed, Troy, Troy again."
没有时间让你再说双关语了！即使你说得还不错。
This is no time for puns! Even good ones.
佩妮，谢尔曼，快点！
Penny, Sherman, quickly!
你们哪里都不准去。
You're not going anywhere.
我已经找到了足够多的理由把这个男孩…
I've seen quite enough to remove the boy...
这两个男孩，都带走。
both boys, from this home.
不，古宁恩夫人，求求你！
No, don't, Ms. Grunion, please!
这是我的错。是我起的头。
This is all my fault. I started it.
我很抱歉，谢尔曼。
I'm so sorry, Sherman.
你不需要道歉，佩妮。
You have nothing to apologize for, Penny.
一只狗从来就不应该被允许领养一个小男孩。
A dog should never have been allowed to adopt a boy in the first place.
现在，过来。
Now, come along.
古宁恩夫人，小心！
Ms. Grunion, be careful!
这是怎么了？
What's happening?
皮博迪先生，帮帮我！
Mr. Peabody, help!
-谢尔曼！      -谢尔曼！
- Sherman!     - Sherman!
嘿！另外两个去了哪里？
Hey! Where did the other two go?
为了协调出现的同一个时空中不能存在两个自我的悖论…
Our cosmic doubles combined in order to reconcile a paradox...
我们的自我互相结合在了一起。
in the space-time continuum.
好的，那挺有道理的。
Okay, that makes sense.
我并不知道刚刚是怎么了…
I don't know what just happened here...
但我知道那不对劲！
but I know it was wrong!
-这个男孩要跟我走！                -皮博迪先生！
- This boy is coming with me!      - Mr. Peabody!
-不，古宁恩夫人！          -让我走！
- No, Ms. Grunion!         - Let me go!
回到这里来！
Get back here!
你弄疼我了！
You're hurting me!
他咬了我！
He bit me!
是的，你好，警察。
Yes, hello, police.
我要报告一起攻击案。
I'd like to report an assault.
一宗咬人事件。
A bite.
皮博迪先生，我们应该怎么办？
Mr. Peabody, what are we gonna do?
快点到这里来。
Get here as soon as possible.
快跑！
Run!
他在绑架孩子！
He's kidnapping the children!
我简直不敢相信你咬了她，皮博迪先生！
I can't believe you bit her, Mr. Peabody!
我知道，谢尔曼，那是不对的。
I know, Sherman, it was wrong.
“不对”？
"Wrong"?
那太酷了！
It was awesome!
现在，我们要回到正确的时空然后消除掉这场混乱。
And now, to return to our proper timeline and erase this mess.
他在那里！他把我的女儿抓进了那个巨大的太空苹果！
There he is! He's got my daughter in that giant space apple!
我的脸麻了。
My face is numb.
太棒了！
Yes!
怎么了？
What's wrong?
时空旅行失败。
Time travel failed.
哦天啊。
Oh, dear.
怎么了皮博迪先生？
What is it, Mr. Peabody?
我们的宇宙分身撞在一起…
Our cosmic doubles colliding...
在宇宙时间的纽带上撕出了一个洞！
ripped a hole in the space-time continuum.
这就是我们没法回到过去的原因。
That's why we didn't get to the past.
嘿，皮博迪先生！
Hey, Peabody!
看起来过去正在来到现在。
Looks like the past is coming to us.
我会抓住你的，狗！
I will get you, dog!
还有你的小男孩！
And your little boy, too!
佩妮！
Penny!
我的新娘！
My bride!
怎么了？
What?
哦，天啊。
Oh, dear.
跟着那个球体！
Follow that orb!
有东西过来了！
Incoming!
你是种什么生物！
What sort of creature are you?
这种生物叫古宁恩！
The name is Grunion!
我爱上她了！
I'm in love!
我只需要找到一个虫洞。
I just need to find a wormhole.
嘿，爱因斯坦，这是红灯！
Hey, Einstein, it's a red light.
嘿，我可是在走路！
Hey, I'm walking, here!
蛋糕！
Cake!
他们在那里！别跟丢了！
There they go. Don't lose them.
我在试着找另一个虫洞…
I'm trying to find another wormhole...
但它们只能带我们到回到现在！
but they all lead back to the present!
时空旅行失败。
Time travel failed.
他在那！追过去！
There he is. After them!
佩妮，我的女王，我知道你在里面。
Penny, my queen, I know you're in there.
我们来了，谢尔曼纳斯！
We're coming, Shermanus!
时空旅行失败。
Time travel failed.
皮博迪先生！
Mr. Peabody!
小心！
Look out!
谢尔曼纳斯，坚持住。
Shermanus, hold on.
我这就将你从这个鸡蛋里解救出来。
We shall release you from this egg.
放下刀然后离开那个未来球体。
Drop the saber and step away from the futuristic orb.
我不接受任何人的命令！
I take orders from no man!
兄弟，别电我。
Don't tase me, bro.
快出来，皮博迪，把你的爪子举起来。
Come out, Peabody, with your paws in the air.
皮博迪先生，你被捕了…
Mr. Peabody, you're under arrest...
因为绑架，鲁莽危害行为…
for kidnapping, reckless endangerment...
还有各种各样的交通违章行为。
And a multiplicity of major traffic violations.
你们不明白。
You don't understand.
宇宙时间的纽带上有条裂缝！
There's a rip in the space-time continuum!
如果你逮捕了我，我就没法修好它…
If you arrest me, I won't be able to fix...
都是废话。这么久以来…
Blah, blah, blah. For too long...
你用你的那些专业术语糊弄了全世界…
you've bamboozled the world with your fancy jargon...
还有这个蝴蝶结…
and that little red tie of yours...
看看这一切都成了什么样。
and look what's come of it.
把他带走！
Take him away!
等等。
Wait.
皮博迪先生！
Mr. Peabody!
谢尔曼！
Sherman!
皮博迪先生会怎样？
What's gonna happen to Mr. Peabody?
你难道不知道咬人的狗会怎样吗？
Don't you know what happens to dogs that bite?
放开我。
Let me go.
你不知道你在干什么。
You don't know what you're doing.
求求你，别让这一切无法挽回。
Please, before it's too late.
等等！
Wait!
给他另一次机会！
Give him another chance.
他有过很多次机会。现在他必须要为他的错误付出代价。
He's through with chances. Now, he has to pay for his mistakes.
但我才是那个犯了所有错误的人。
But I'm the one who made all the mistakes.
我才是那个未经允许就用了WABAC的人。
I'm the one who used the WABAC without permission.
皮博迪先生唯一犯下的错…
The only mistake Mr. Peabody ever made...
就是收养了我。
was me.
谢尔曼。
Sherman.
你说得一点都没错，谢尔曼。
You're absolutely right, Sherman.
这只狗可以成为一个男孩什么样的父亲？
What kind of a father could this dog ever be to a boy?
也许你说得没错，古宁恩夫人。
Maybe you're right, Ms. Grunion.
但有一件事你没有考虑到。
But there's one thing you haven't considered.
什么事？
What's that?
我也是一只狗！
I'm a dog, too!
如果成为一只狗意味着和皮博迪先生一样…
If being a dog means you're like Mr. Peabody...
从来不会背叛你…
who never turns his back on you...
在你失落的时候帮你振作起来…
and who's always there to pick you up when you fall...
无论你搞砸了多少次都会一如既往地爱你…
and loves you no matter how many times you mess up...
如果一只狗是这样的话…
if that's what it means to be a dog...
那么，是的，我也是一只狗！
then, yeah, I'm a dog, too!
我也是一只狗。
I'm a dog, too.
我也是一只狗！
I'm a dog, too!
I'm a dog as well!
一只狮子狗！
A poodle dog!
我也是一只狗。
I am a dog, too.
我也是一只狗！
Ditto on that dog thing!
我也是一只狗。
I'm a dog, too.
I am a dog as well.
-我也是一只狗。          -我也是一只狗。
- I'm a dog, too.        - I'm a dog, too.
我也是一只狗。
I'm a dog, too.
我是个斯巴达克斯党！
I'm Spartacus!
好的，行，你们都是狗但你们没法改变法律。
All right, fine, you're all dogs, but you can't change the law.
我知道有谁可以。
I know someone who can.
乔治华盛顿。
George Washington.
我们持有一些真理来让我们有自知之明…
We hold these truths to be self-evident...
例如所有人，还有一些狗，都是生来平等的。
that all men, and some dogs, are created equal.
我以总统的名义赦免皮博迪先生。
I hereby award Mr. Peabody a presidential pardon.
我也是。（林肯……）
Me, too.
我做过更糟的。（肯尼迪……）
I've done worse.
皮博迪先生，看！
Mr. Peabody, look!
它越来越近了！
It's getting closer!
我们要怎么办？
What are we going to do?
史上最聪明的天才都聚集在这里了！
This is the greatest collection of geniuses ever assembled!
我们一定可以想出另一种方法帮我们回到过去。
Surely we can come up with another way of getting to the past.
我可以造一个弹射器。
I can build a catapult.
我们可以飞得非常快。（右边的那个是甘地）
We go very fast.
但是，要记住，当你接近光速时…
But, remember, as you approach the speed of light...
重力会变得非常强大。
gravity will get too strong.
是的。“对于每一个动作，都有一个大小相等，方向相反的反作用力。”（牛顿…）
Indeed. "For every action, there is an equal and opposite reaction."
让我们往那个大洞脸上打一拳如何？
How about we just punch that big hole in the face?
我有个主意。
I have an idea.
嘿，大伙，我有个主意了！
Hey, everybody, I have an idea!
什么主意，谢尔曼？
Yes, what is it, Sherman?
咱们去未来怎么样？
Why not go to the future?
未来？
The future?
我从没去过那里，所以也许那里不会一团糟。
I've never been there before, so it's probably not as messed up.
谢尔曼，就是这个！你在想的和我一样吗？
Sherman, that's it! Are you thinking what I'm thinking?
不总是这样。
Not usually.
这就跟你们刚刚说一样的…
It's exactly what you all just said...
只不过完全相反！
except the total opposite!
如果我们设定WABAC穿越到未来，以非常非常快的速度…
If we set the WABAC for the future, and go very, very fast...
制造一个重力场…
we'll create our own gravitational field...
用大小相等且方向相反的力…
that's equal and opposite...
进入到宇宙时间纽带的裂缝中去！
to the rip in the space-time continuum!
哦，天啊…
Oh, my...
我听不懂。
I don't get it.
我们要飞上去往那个大洞脸上打一拳！
We're gonna fly up there and punch that big hole in the face!
太棒了！
Yes!
谢尔曼，你真是个天才。
Sherman, you're a genius.
但是，皮博迪…
But, Peabody...
你们要去到多久以后的未来？
how far into the future must you go?
几秒钟就够了，然后我们就弹回来。
Just a few seconds ought to do it, and then we'll slingshot right back.
你确定这会有用吗？
Are you sure this is going to work?
别担心，佩妮。
Don't worry, Penny.
要知道，我可是个…
Just remember, I'm a...
天才！
genius!
谢尔曼…
Sherman...
我需要重新设定WABAC。
I need to reprogram the WABAC.
好的，皮博迪先生。
All right, Mr. Peabody.
那意味着你来驾驶。
That means you have to drive.
为了要跃进未来…
In order to make the leap into the future...
WABAC必须要有很快的速度。
the WABAC will have to go very fast.
比之前的还要快！
Faster than it's ever gone before!
你准备好了吗，谢尔曼？
Are you ready, Sherman?
我准备好了。
I'm ready.
挺住，谢尔曼，你行的。
Come on, Sherman, you can do it.
现在吗，皮博迪先生？
Now, Mr. Peabody?
谢尔曼，我们需要更快的速度。
Sherman, we need more speed.
现在？
Now?
再快一点！
Just a little more!
还不行，谢尔曼。
Not yet, Sherman.
还不行。
Not yet.
就是现在！
Now!
再见了。
Farewell!
你还没看看我呢，皮博迪。
You haven't seen the last of me, Peabody.
你最终会犯下错误的，当你真的犯错的时候…
You'll make a mistake eventually, and when you do...
我就会抓住你的！
I'll be there!
古宁恩是我的了！
The Grunion is mine!
加油，谢尔曼。加油！
Come on, Sherman. Come on!
如果你想在我回家前看电视…
If you want to watch television before I get home...
只要轻轻按三次“输入”键…
simply press "input" three times...
然后就和平时一样用远程遥控器。
and then use the remote control as usual.
好的，谢尔曼。
Yes, Sherman.
如果你担心你在家庭教师协会交不到朋友…
And if you're worried about making friends at the PTA meeting...
可以试着带点点心给别人。
consider bringing snacks for everyone.
百吉饼很受欢迎的。
Bagels are always appreciated.
好的，谢尔曼。
Yes, Sherman.
还有要记住，皮博迪先生…
And remember, Mr. Peabody...
今天放学后我还要参加机器人俱乐部。
I have robotics club after school today.
谢尔曼，等等。
Sherman, wait.
怎么了，皮博迪先生？
Yes, Mr. Peabody?
我爱你，谢尔曼。
I love you, Sherman.
我也很爱你，皮博迪先生。
I have a deep regard for you as well, Mr. Peabody.
嘿，皮博迪先生！
Hey, Mr. Peabody!
嘿，谢尔曼！
Hey, Sherman!
等等我！
Wait up!
毫无疑问。
No doubt about it.
每只狗都应该收养一个男孩。
Every dog should have a boy.
我现在宣布你们是夫妻了。
I now pronounce you husband and wife.
你可以亲古宁恩了。
You may kiss the Grunion.
过来这边，大兵！
Come here, soldier.
翻译：男厕有女生          校对：冀茗樱
谢谢观看！
新浪微博：男厕有女生 ；冀茗樱